# 哈喽 大家好
Hello, everyone!
# 今天我用这个玉米和大家分享一个玉米烙
Today I will use corn to make corn pancake.
# 就只要玉米鸡蛋和（土豆）淀粉
The only ingredients are corn, eggs, and potato starch.
# 就可以做一个大大的饼
And we can make a large pancake.
# 又脆又好吃
It is crispy and delicious.
# 我们这次用的是鲜玉米
We will use fresh corns.
# 这个（玉米）浆浆都冒出来了
The corn juice is effusing.
# 这玉米我们就直接把它切下来
We need to cut the corn off the cob.
# 如果你们没有鲜玉米
However, if you don't have fresh corn,
# 可以买（玉米）罐头
you can use canned corn instead.
# 四伯爷 吃过玉米罐头吗
Uncle, have you ever tried canned corn?
# 没有
No.
# 然后这个玉米棒子
As for the cobs,
# 我们很多人切了之后就把它丢了
many people will throw them away into the trash.
# 其实这个切了之后
However, we can chop them into chunks,
# 放点排骨 放点马蹄之类的煲汤特别好喝
add some pork ribs, and water-chestnuts to make a delicious bowl of soup.
# 然后打一个鸡蛋
Next, we need to crack an egg.
# 鸡蛋大家记住 只要蛋黄不要蛋清
However, we will only use the yolk.
# 蛋清放下去了之后会脱粉
The potato starch will fall off if we add in the egg white.
# 然后把蛋黄滤出来
We need to strain out the yolk only.
# 蛋黄放下去把它拌匀
After adding the yolk, we need to mix it with the corn.
# 这个蛋清等会我们用来做蛋花汤
Later on, we can make egg flower soup with the egg white.
# 可以安
Sure.
# 然后我们这个你看黄黄的是吧
See, it's pretty yellow.
# 蛋黄加进去后
After adding the yolk,
# 颜色也很好看
the color looks nice.
# 金黄金黄的安逸
Nice, its golden.
# 然后我们再加一点吉士粉
Then, we will add some custard powder.
# 吉士粉它也可以说是一种香精嘛
Custard powder is actually a type of food essence.
# 不喜欢的话可以不加
You can ignore this step if you don't like it.
# 你看 现在它粘粘的
See, it is sticky now.
# 对吧
Yea.
# 肯定撒
Sure.
# 吉士粉放了之后
After mixing the custard powder,
# 再抓一把淀粉
we will add some potato starch.
# 先抓一小把
We will start with a small amount of starch.
# 然后给它拌匀
And mix it well.
# 因为这个蛋黄它自带粘性
Because the yolk itself is sticky
# 我们裹上去之后
after we coat the corn with starch,
# 然后再加一点点（淀粉）
we will add some starch again.
# 就是让它颗粒分明
To make the kernels clear.
# 可以了
Done.
# 现在我去炸
Now let's deep fry it.
# 马上就可以炸好
This will be quick.
# 炸好之后多大一个饼饼儿
Afterwards we will have a big corn pancake.
# 香 是不
Smells pretty good, right?
# 那里面有一点点香精
There is a little bit MSG in it.
# 但是是食用香精
But because it is MSG,
# 可以吃的
it is safe to eat.
# 用它烙饼肯定很安逸
I bet the pancake will be good.
# 烙饼肯定好吃
Definetly.
# 火是不是小了点
Isn't the heat too low?
# 来火了撒
Now it's coming up.
# 放点白糖
We can add some sugar on it.
# 放点白糖好干（吃）点
To make it tastes better.
# 你吃得没得好甜的哦
Have you tried it yet? It's so sweet.
# 少放一点
Then we need to add a little less sugar.
# 要得要得
Sure.
# 我晓得你吃得厚
I know you like more flavor.
# 厚点吃着扎实点
More flavor is more stable.
# 吃得厚 吃得老
Stable, and tough.
# 吃得老
Tough.
# 钓鱼才说吃得老都嘛
Aren't you only suppose to say this when you go fishing?
# 随便啥子都要吃老点的
No,
# 做生意都要吃得老点的
you also need to be tough as a businessman.
# 不吃老点要吃亏
Otherwise you will lose money.
# 我们两爷子就拿手嘛
Can we just use our hands?
# 要得
Sure.
# 自己弄哦
Help yourself, uncle.
# 这个很脆
It's crunchy.
# 蘸点白糖
I will dip it into the sugar.
# 安逸
Nice.
# 很脆 大家可以在家里面试一下
It's crunchy, you should try this at home.
# 又香又甜
Sweet and delicious.
# 在饭店里面的话 还要再做薄一点
The pancake will be thiner if you were to eat this in a restaurant.
# 还要炸得更硬一些
Add they will deep fry it even more.
# 然后切成三角形
And then cut it into triangles.
# 最后撒上白糖 撒上西红柿颗粒
Finally, sprinkle with sugar and tomato chunks.
# 我叫伯娘来吃
I will go get aunty to try this.
# 伯娘
Aunty!
# 这个好吃
This is good.
# 伯娘过来吃东西
Aunty, come and try this.
# 你不快点我吃完了哦
Or I will eat it all,
# 你再不来
if you don't come.
# 等会我们俩都吃完了
We would eat this all if you come too late.
# 我们直接用手掰的
We will use our hands.
# 用手掰的呀
Ok, I will use my hand as well.
# 试一下
Let me try it.
# 放的白糖是不哦
Did you put sugar in it.
# 放的粉子（土豆淀粉）
It's potato starch, actually.
# 先炸 然后再撒的白糖
We deep fried it, then sprinkled some sugar.
# 真的好吃
It's really delicious.
# 你看这一截全部都是我掰来吃了的
See, I just ate all those.
# 你呀
You,
# 你好厉害哦
you are so good...hahaha.
# 好吃
So good.
# 大口吃哦
Take a big bite.
# 大口大口的
Big bite.
# 你咬得动啊
Isn't this too tough for you to eat?
# 咬得动
I think he has no problem eating it.
# 好厉害哦
So good.
# 这个是外酥里嫩
It's crunchy outside and tender inside.
# 好吃
Delicious
# 你们先吃 我收拾一下
You guys eat, I will clean those up.